# Liu, Teng-Yuan (Shuk Liu)

biz.shuk@gmail.com, Skype: initialshuk Linkedin, TW (886) 0902-398163

**Summary** last updated: 2019-01-05

Full-Stack engineer aim services on the internet, mostly worked on back-end and experienced in web app, game development, analysis, AWS, CI/CD, and Agile methodology. Working on Linux(Ubuntu) or Mac and having deep understanding of git and release management. Designing scalable system with higher available is part of my job and analyzing pros and cons of technique depends on resources. Currently study toward Golang(backend), js(backend or frontend), and cluster management.

# **Skills**

Certificate: AWS - Solution Architect - associate

Language: Java (Spring), js(reactjs angularjs), PHP, Perl, Bash, HTML5, CSS (SASS), Go, Python

Server as a user: Kubernetes, Mysql(schema design), Mongo, Memcached, Chef-solo Server as a admin: Linux, Git, Nginx, Docker, Jenkins, Ansible, Apache HTTP, BIND

Concept: OO, CI/CD, MVC, Network, RWD, Cache, HA, Scalability, Consistency, BDD, Agile, Lean

# **Work Experience**

#### Engineer | Innova Solutions | Naihu, TW

28/02/2017 - Present

Cloud solution provider. In this branch, it's BOT for Change Health Care(CHC) in U.S.

- Work on AWS, Java (Spring), Scrum, Js, CSS. Small Scrum team with SM of CHC in US.
- Develop, give suggestions on projects, and assist to manage the team.
- Went through whole stack of legacy deployment process and migrated all applications to new cloud architecture(not app) successfully and smoothly.
- Tuning java app through jstack jstat jmap in rare cases.

#### Cloud Engineer | Shanghai Droi Tech Co. Ltd. | Taipei 101, TW

13/07/2015 - 13/05/2016

Internet company, 500+ people, from device hardware to backend as a cloud application solution (e.g. parse.com)

- Worked on Bash, Lua, Linux, Nginx, Docker, Jenkins, Ansible, Kubenetes, Mongo, PostgreSQL.
- Model "Backend As A Service" arch including app commit flow and integrate with Jenkins toward Kubernetes.
- End to end test framework for developers on the platform, also including syntax check, api detected, and request profiling.
- Cli tool to make linear version control, let user manage their own code simply.

### Game and BI developer | Gamesofa Inc. | Taipei, TW

28/11/2012 - 17/04/2015

Online Game company, 200 people, self-made games including Mahjong, Poker, FPS, and RPG

- Worked on PHP, Perl, HTML5, Javascript, AngularJS, CSS, Linux, Apache, Mysql, Memcache.
- Get requirements from PM, check the scope in each small sprint. Eventually, collaborate with QA and delivery.
- Win8 App "Godgame big two" by HTML5, integrate billing services, interact with back-end, adjust UI.
- Responsible for "Godgame Texas Hold'em" server side events and features, e.g. general friend list for multiple games, and fix bugs.
- Omaha game rule is to pick in two sets, one pick 2 in 4 and other pick 3 in 5, to combine biggest card type and compare with others people, using hash and combined with card type probability to reduce the performance
- Developed survey system and deploy to different region to solve global location latency issue, and customized options for ordered sequential options avoiding making useless data.
- User analyzing system showing user retention rate, payment and activated situations with selected group. It's easy for product manager and marketing specialist. And we may do some A/B testing for groups of user.
- Refactor and maintain existing systems, customer service system.

#### Web developer | National Central University | Jongli, Taiwan

03/2010 - 06/2011

- [PHP] Setup websites, bypass library system for ebook search, saving \$20000 at least and maintaining fee
- [PHP] Refactor facility application system

## Projects and self-study

- Google C++ education (06/2016 06/2016) Lee Code with Python, C++, javascript (05/2016 present)
- **Personal web site** (04/2015 06/2015) with ReactJS, RWD
- Free code camp with HTML5 (09/2015 11/2015)

## Education

- M.S. in CS, National Central University, Jongli , Taiwan, 2009.09-2011.06, June. (Java, PHP)
- B.S. in CS, National Dong-Hua University, Hualien, Taiwan, 2004.09-2009.06, Jan. (C, C++, PHP)